I have a confession to make
and I have to the first confession is
that well thank you Richard for letting
everybody know that I'm from IT I'm not
a finance guy so normally my world is
within the mainframes the monitors I'm
always at the back office so what what
am I doing here
it really is strange for me to speak in
front of a big crowd so I am really
petrified my friends I'm not used to
this so it's not a pleasure for me to
speak that's the first revelation the
second one is the topic that I'm
supposed to discuss today in show tech
we're not even in tech and I just used
insured accurate I could get in one of
the topics here in today's conference
because we're not insured that we're a
life insurance company and we are the
youngest at that so we're being in the
market for four and a half years just in
the Philippines so those are my two
revelations what is that okay my friends
so if I bungle my words please forgive
me so I won't go through all of this but
this is my plan if I can get through the
end what is the landscape yeah FWD has
been in the Philippines for less than
five years four and a half years and we
are in an industry dominated by hundred
twenty-five year old companies and we're
just a toddler compared to these
companies in the Philippines the average
life insurers about 70 years our plan is
to reinforce FWD as a challenger brand
and I'm so
interested with with the stories of mr.
mr. justo how they transform Union Bank
into a technology company and we are
very digital we invest 60% of eyepiece
budget in digital hopefully we're
innovative enough and more importantly
is speed so that we can create more
compelling and value propositions or
customers so what is the story so far we
started 2014 we were dead last
number 33 that is expected a new entrant
in 2014 we were dead last but something
interesting happened a couple of years
back 2017 we started getting up to
ranking so you have number 10 and this
was quite amazing for such a company we
were just three year old three years old
then and would you like to know where we
are right now
at least 2018 is that something that's
interesting for everyone I don't think
it's that interesting enough do you want
you want to know 2018 this is as of the
third quarter of 2018 unofficial and
we're already number eight and what's
more interesting is that we are in terms
of growth rate we are beating the
industry growth rate by three times as
well that actually this is based on 2017
figures we still need to get the 2018
figures for fourth quarter that is very
inspiring for a newcomer like FWD and we
talked about customers we talked about
technology and more importantly the the
reason why we are here is the purpose
our purpose is we have to change the way
people feel about insurance not about
technology not about process it's about
behavior it is about us
people and can have a very short quick
raise of hands how many in this room
have insurance policies
I am so life insurance policies by the
way so if I think mark mentioned that
that 20 15 to 20 million have bank
accounts in life insurance only
two-and-a-half percent have life
insurance policy in the Philippines and
for those who raise their hands are you
happy with your insurance policy
III can't really I can barely hear you
but you have a contract with your
insurer and normally your contract is
about 20 pages have you actually read
your insurance policy no that's a very
strong know that that I've heard from
the audience and that is also
interesting so in order for you to for
us to change the way people feel about
insurance we have to build that trust
and I'm from IT I am NOT from the
classroom experience so I'm mostly
talking to ones and zeros but what does
it mean for us we had to start with a
very basic contract that the customer
has which is our insurance policy now we
we saw that insurance policies were
pardon my my I don't want to undermine
our lawyer friends here if we have
lawyers in the room they are not easy to
read in fact they're not using common
English terms in fact using insurance
jargons
and it is tough to get them passed
through page number three why is that
significant ask me why you know why that
is significant because your benefit is
actually on page number four so if
you're only looking at to page number
three and then decide not to read it at
all that and then you
missed out on the benefits which is on
page number four so what we did for one
of our products if we use common English
terms that is good enough to be
understood by a fifth grader these were
almost comic book-like
if you wanted to build trust you wanted
to ensure that they understand what
they're signing up for is that is that
logical now what's more interesting is
after that so we had an experiment and
they couldn't get past page three when
we revised our policies they started
reading up to page 11 and they started
asking questions which is the thing that
we wanted to elicit from our customers
and more importantly I want to highlight
this statement reduce exclusions one of
the reasons and bother me because I
think we are the only life insurer in
this in this session but one of the
reasons why there's a big distrust is
that it seems that there's a perception
that insurance company or life insurance
companies are only after the premiums
after you paid for the premiums and then
you're about to claim they would use
every single word in the contract not to
pay your claim there is a perception
that is not the truth that is far from
the truth
so if you recall my first slide it's
somebody who's jumping from an airplane
we had to reduce exclusions that means
we cover even if you're doing extreme
sports we cover even if you're doing
parasailing we cover it even if you're
doing bungee jumping because we want
everyone to live their life to the
fullest and that's that's what is very
compelling for us we wanted people to be
safe and don't worry about financial
protection because because we have we
are covering their backs
and I think Mike also also mentioned
about digital it is difficult for us in
the life insurance industry to remove
paper in the point-of-sale
and it took us four iterations to make
it work our first three ith ins failed
we were using tablets for the signatures
and we were using a photo of your ID
uploaded as a form of your documents and
we failed in the first we try however
the the light started to shine in our
fourth iteration this is actually
version 5 it was a charm
it was the most one of the most stable
platform that we had and after we have
implemented version 4 so we I to rate it
faster we learn from our insure tech
friends how to do it much faster so our
digital distribution is 100% paperless
and we failed three times 2016 I was
given an order actually more of a
request by my by my CEO and there was a
challenge because there was it was
September early September and people
were afraid to go out of of their houses
because there was a bombing attack and
it's so strange in the Philippines
because September we have the longest
Christmas season on the planet we start
Christmas in September and then we end
February 13 so we had that opportunity
so why not create a product that
protects them from terror terrorism and
but the mandate for me was that to
create this product in a new platform in
30 days I said ok boss when was the last
time we created product Oh we created a
product two years ago
okay do we have a digital platform of
course not nookie that's why you're here
and those were the two challenges that
were given to me create a new product in
a new platform in 30 days so I need to
do this otherwise I'll be fired so do
you want to know the story how the story
ended we actually did launch a new
product in a new platform in 21 days so
I was able to say nine days from from
what my boss originally expected me to
do and this product is called peace it's
a financial protection product that
covers you in in case you die of a
terrorist bombing all over the globe for
just six pesos a day and this is
compelling because we we were able to do
something different and apart from that
we're also engaging our customers more
to our digital community and if I have
time later is it okay if I play a very
short video of how passionate we are
adaptability and in fact we are so
passionate about trying to breach the
boundaries of what we can do we started
doing some things that are not not no
ordinary insurance company we do we
actually publish a song we publish a
song that was sang by mix sang and
composed by mix is from the Miss Saigon
in London and if I have time later can i
is it okay if I play that so we're not
just a life insurance company we're also
a song publisher and this is how we
engage our target customers on this
slide because this is a FinTech
conference
everybody has a financial payment so we
can I skip this everybody has a
financial solution software we've been
discussing about customers and another
challenge given to me by my boss okay
new key you were very successful in in
the 30 days or 21 days launch
new digital platform I want to do
something else I want you to create
another platform and revive or a 16-1
okay what was the challenge the
challenge was we had an existing
customer portal in a custom report of
adoption or usage is less than 9% okay
so what what do you need me to do sir he
said we needed to increase adoption and
usage by 35% and I want you to do this
in 90 days okay I was given another
challenge on another job threatening
challenge for me so we pondered and
looked at whatever tools we can use
because if we used existing tools that
our programmers had at that time it
would have taken us six months to
develop so we needed something quicker
so going back to the piece product we
use the same platform and from hammer
and nail technology we call this
technology
nail gun technology and this is what we
call part of my slang and IT a
superpower a superpower is something
that allows you to lift heavy paying
heavy things like there are nothing if
you also have super speed so using this
new technology we were able to create
this new platform we called it tap and
this new platform was not developed and
delivered in 90 days so I failed the
mark so I thought I was I was gonna get
fired Richard but then we were able to
deliver it in 92 days so this new
platform actually is a living platform
because we were finally able to adopt
the same speed as a shirt or FinTech
does if there are Christmas season
holidays Valentine season we would
change the screens as needed and the
most compelling thing that we
experienced during this time because
this is posted in the App Store whenever
one one of our customers would post a
comment and then that comment
immediately will be replied to by one of
our six age
the CRR the CRM system will allow an
auto ticket sent to our DevOps team in
IP within the hour we're able to get
that complaint if it's a bug that we
need to fix our DevOps team develops
test it and deploys it before the end of
the day and the next time the client
locks on to the app it's fixed my
friends imagine if you were that client
regardless of who you are regardless of
whether you are you are a c-level or
just an employee that's how much value
were giving to you how would you feel
customer interaction
I'm from IT I am not from sales by the
way and we mentioned a lot about digital
data but the most interesting story that
I wanted to share with you here is when
I was coming from another industry from
the telco industry we failed a number of
times in investing for the wrong EDW
infrastructure there was one project
that when that cost us ten million
dollars that never saw the light of day
and the project that we did using
another superpower allowed us to deliver
a new edw infrastructure enterprise data
warehouse infrastructure in 4.5 months
at a fraction of the cost we've learned
from our previous industries the
mistakes and this is traditional EDW the
results so far are you still there my
friends are you interested to know the
results so far Ford for FWD let's start
with customer experience
we are rated by our CX Isis these are
oops
okay can you please go back to my slide
so the results so far for cxi in 2017
RCX I score was 75% last year we were
able to improve this to 80% if for the
first time we are first in this category
in their life insurance industry
customer complaints ratio and this is
something I'm willing I got permission
to share with all of you it's point zero
zero one percent which has been which
has been stable since 2016 brand
awareness in 2014 we were no one nobody
zero to 15 percent and we doubled it in
2018 but the most compelling reason that
I wanted to share it maybe for the CEO
in the room is our growth rate for at
least for the third quarter of 2018 we
actually grew four times the industry
average in the third quarter and that's
what customer experience satisfaction
brings us so apologies for these slides
my marketing team inserted this so I had
these are mandatory slides that I had to
share with you we have three million
customers and 4,600 employees 16,000
agents and managing an asset of about 28
billion dollars we are a pan-asian
insurance company we are our
headquarters is in Hong Kong and the
Philippines is one of our greenfield
markets we started like a start-up our
board of directors are very demanding
board of directors include the former
BSP governor chairman koo isha and
another expat from another insurance
company peters is my boss my my
demanding boss
what are the takeaways it's not anymore
about the big and the small the battle
is not about anymore about the big and
small it is about the fast and the slow
we're not as big as our 90 year old or
125 year old
competitors but we are fast because
speed kills
industry dinosaurs can everybody say
this speed kills industry dinosaurs you
have to believe in that statement
because otherwise you will be overrun my
friends if you become too complacent you
might be overrun by speed freaks like
FWD I mentioned to you at the start of
my my speech that I was just stuck in
the data center I don't know people I
know computers but I had this vision
when I saw Gordon Ramsay that you can
see that chefs are not anymore stuck in
the kitchen they go out to the customers
and they asks the customers how is my
food do you think we can still improve
and the insight that he is getting
directly by speaking to customers is
amazing these are data these are pain
points of course people would be very
kind to tell you your food tastes really
nice and wouldn't probably some of them
might not be so trap in telling them
about the real pain points but ID needed
to do the same so we went out of the
data center and we went to the customers
the first thing we needed to do was to
change and we started people we started
with people we had to get to know more
about our customers and in one of the
speaker's they also shared about
creating personas for customers
visualizing every single step of the
customer journey
and looking at opportunities where to
improve on that customer journey so that
we know the experience and more
importantly this insights from the
customer journey experiences were mapped
into a design to come up with a solution
and we were not perfect when we launched
it after 90 days of after 21 days but we
iterated daily and sometimes even hourly
for the first time in the company where
we I was confronted with with a huge
list of technical debts for the first
time we were asking the business where
are your requests
where are your demands because we're
ready with the platform ours our league
of superheroes have superpowers that can
immediately turn the dime around and
more importantly we had to identify
people with the right culture because
not everybody's cut out to be to be fast
some can be traditional and we realized
that in terms of the process and this is
something that's close to my heart we
allow our people to create their own
processes we allow them to jab their own
experiences because once they own the
process they would follow it so we had
adopted agile scrum Kanban and for
traditional thinkers for the back-office
operations we still use waterfall SDLC
and linear development on the platform
this is where I love this is this is my
heart it's on the superpowers that we
that we used offline you can ask me
probably on the sidelines what the
superpowers are we use rad both on the
front end on the middle development of
our api's including the back end we
still use mainframes
and that's that's a that's something
that we still maintain and most
financial insurance companies have in my
running out of time
so these new tools we call superpowers
at the one that drives our technology
team so our technology team are now
being branded as rockstars I never even
imagined to be called a rockstar because
I don't even know how to speak in front
of the public that take away my dear
friends is the real look at the real
pain points of the customers and then
work on resolving these pain points
regardless of who your customers are
even sea levels and even even new
policyholders because that's how you
gain trust and like what does mention in
the other in the other talks and I think
this is this is a resemblance from the
other from the other talks is technology
is only one part of the solution the
need takes over at this point if I am
allowed can I play the short video that
I wrote is called fill my cup basically
it's about living your life to the
fullest I mean we're only given a
certain amount of time on this earth and
we want to be filling it up with
everything that we can possibly do I
mean there's so many amazing things to
see and to do in this world and what I
love about the whole process of being
involved with with FWD is that their
motto is not about hold don't do that
don't do that be careful be you know
they said no we want you to live your
life to the fullest and we'll be here
you know just in case something may go
wrong you know we're here to back you up
fortune favors the brave and FWD is
there to help you be brave
[Music]
I can tell you about my day of sorrow
I'd rather sing come why don't you chill
all day all night I know it's gonna be
oh yeah I could sing about my
I rather autumn here and eat back
to my desk
yeesh
[Music]
[Applause]
yeah
fear is my passion and I got plenty more
of love to give
[Music]
[Applause]
the passion imagination
[Music]
thank you very much my dear friends and
thank you for accommodating me despite
my my less less I can't really speak
that well and one more thing I want to
leave with you is this live your life to
the fullest and be brave my dear friends
thank you
[Music]